Guide to the Charles James Hendley Papers TAM.109
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Academic Freedom Material, 1928-1961; 309664
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee (New York State Joint Legislative Committee on the State Education System), 1940; 309673 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee, Jan 1941 - May 1941; 309674 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee, Jun 1941 - Dec 1941; 309675 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee, 1942-1943, 1951-1952, undated; 309676 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee: Coudert and Boris Brasol, 1941-1942, undated; 309677 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee: Hendley and the Teachers Union, 1940; 309678 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee: Hendley and the Teachers Union, 1940-1942; 309679 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1933-1939; 309681 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1940-1949; 309682 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1950; 309683 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1951; 309684 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, Feb 1952 - Oct 1952; 309685 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, Nov 1952 - Dec 1952; 309686 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1953; 309687 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1954-1957; 309688 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals, 1958-1959, undated; 309689 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals: Louis Jaffe, 1948 - [1952]; 309690 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals: Sylvia Schneiderman, 1950; 309691 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Teacher Harassment, Dismissals: Dale Zysman, 1941-1942; 309692 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Series V: Subject Files, 1914-1962; 309693
  This series contains a wide variety of materials touching on Hendley's professional, political and cultural interests. Examples include federal aid to education, the Spanish Civil War, anti-communism and red-baiting, civil rights and the segregation of schools, separation of church and state, reading retardation and education during wartime. Hendley's involvement in Socialism and in the Communist Party is reflected, including his association with The Worker. Organizations such as the American Federation of Teachers (AFT), the American Labor Party (ALP) and the National Education Association (NEA) are represented, along with smaller teacher associations and teacher unions outside the New York area. Files are included on individuals such as Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Morris Schappes and the Rosenbergs. There are many newpaper clippings, collected over thirty years, that document educational, political and labor issues. The series contains examples of many serials as well as pamphlets and other publications, including several of particular interest -- The Flivver King by Upton Sinclair, On Scabs by Jack London, a small book of anti-Nazi humor, and The Challenger, a comic with liberal superheroes published by the Interfaith Committee of the Protestant Digest in the mid-1940s.
  - Amalgamated Textile Workers of America, 1919-1920; 309747 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL) v. Congress of Industrial Organizatons (CIO), 1937-1938, undated; 309748 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - AFL v. CIO: Communist Wreckers in American Labor, by Benjamin Stolberg, 1939; 309749 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - American Federation of Teachers: The American Teacher, 1932-1941; 309796 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Constitution, 1936-1940; 309797 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Convention Materials (15th, 16th, 18th, 20th, 21st, 22nd, 23rd), 1931-1939; 309798 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Convention Materials (24th), 1940; 309799 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Correspondence, 1937-1941; 309800 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Dare the Teachers Do Their Public Duty? (Pre-WWII Program of Action), undated; 309801 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Educational Defense Committee, undated; 309802 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Executive Council Material, 1933-1938; 309803 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Executive Council Material, 1939-1941, undated; 309804 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Finances, 1932-1941; 309805 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Printed Material - Pamphlets, Reprints, Bulletins, 1933-1938, undated; 309806 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Roster of Locals, 1939; 309807 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - American Federation of Teachers: Various Reports, Statements and other Items, 1935-1942, undated; 309808 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - American Labor Party, 1938-1945; 309809 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - American Labor Party, 1946-1947; 309810 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - American Labor Party, 1948; 309811 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - American Labor Party, 1949-1950; 309812 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - American Labor Party, 1951-1953, undated; 309813 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - American Russian Institute, 1947, 1948; 309814 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - American Student Union, 1937-1941, undated; 309815 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting, 1941, 1948-1959, undated; 309816 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: Earl Browder, 1941-1942, 1952; 309817 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: Harry Bridges and Longshoremen, 1942, undated; 309818 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: Henry Steele Commager - Articles, 1947, 1953; 309819 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: House Committee on Un-American Activities / Dies Committee, 1939-1960; 309820 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: McCarthy, Joseph, 1952-1953, undated; 309822 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: Smith Act, 1948-1960, undated; 309823 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: Smith Act - Henry Winston, 1960; 309824 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Communism, Red Baiting: United Nations Probe, Oct 1952; 309825 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Nuclear Flyers, Pamphlets, Articles and Petitions, 1950-1962, undated; 309826 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1938-1950; 309827 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Anti-War Material, 1929, 1937-1940, undated; 309828 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Anti-War Material, 1948-1952, undated; 309829 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Bestor, Arthur E., Jr., 1952; 309830 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - "A Bill of Duties for the American People": Adopted by National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1941; 309831 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Bland Bill (HR 5074), 1941; 309832 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Blank Forms, Stationery, undated; 309833 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Books, Pamphlets and Other Documents: Lists, Announcements, 1942, undated; 309834 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Brookwood Labor College and Arthur Calhoun, 1929; 309835 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Brownell, Herbert, Jr. v. United May Day Committee (Subversive Activities Control Board), 1956; 309836 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - The Challenger: Comic (published by the Interfaith Committee of the Protestant Digest, Inc.), 1946; 309837 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Child Labor, 1924, 1927; 309838 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Childs, John L., 1936, 1938; 309839 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - City Housing Corporation: Sunnyside Gardens, 1928; 309840 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Civil Rights: Articles, Newsletters, Events, Correspondence, 1941-1948; 309841 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Civil Rights: Articles, Newsletters, Events, Correspondence, 1949-1960, undated; 309842 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Classes, Seminars and School Announcements, 1930-1961, undated; 309843 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Committee to Preserve Tenure, 1942; 309844 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Commonwealth College, 1940; 309845 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Communist Control Act of 1954 (Includes Letter from Hubert Humphrey), 309846 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Communist Party, 1957; 309847 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Communist Party, 1958-1961, undated; 309848 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Communist Party: The New Masses, 1947; 309849 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Communist Party: Section Committee Meetings and Related Material, 1957-1958; 309850 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Compulsory Military Service, 1940, undated; 309851 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Cooperative College for Social Reconstruction (New College), 1937; 309852 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Curriculum and Teaching Materials, 1923-1938; 309853 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Curriculum and Teaching Materials, 1941-1948; 309854 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Curriculum and Teaching Materials, 1950-1954, 1961, undated; 309855 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Davis, Jerome, 1936, 1940; 309866 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Dewey, John: The Crisis in Education and Why I Am a Member of the Teachers Union, 1933, undated; 309867 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Dodd, Bella: My Testimony to the Faith, 1952; 309868 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Downtown Community School, 1944; 309871 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Education: General, 1925, 1939-1952; 309890 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Education: General, 1953-1960, undated; 309891 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Education during Wartime, 1939 - Apr 1942; 309892 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Education during Wartime, May 1942 - 1943; 309893 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Education during Wartime, 1944-1946, 1950, undated; 309894 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Education in New York State: Preliminary Annual Report, 1949; 309895 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Educational Organizations and Associations: Various, 1939-1953, undated; 309896 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Eight Hour Work-Day Conference, 1917-1919; 309897 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Eight Hour Work-Day Conference, [1917-1919]; 309898 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Eight Hour Work-Day Conference: Delegate Credentials, 1918-1919; 309899 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Election Materials: Various, 1933-1937, undated; 309900 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Ethical Culture Schools, 1943-1956, undated; 309901 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1934-1946; 309902 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1947-1950, undated; 309903 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Federal Aid to Education: Bills, 1939, 1945; 309904 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Federal Aid to Education: Separation of Church and State Issue, 1939-1945; 309905 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Federal Aid to Education: Separation of Church and State Issue, 1947-1948, undated; 309906 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Five Cent Fare Committee, 1940; 309907 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - The Flivver King: Upton Sinclair novel, First Edition, Published by the United Auto Workers, 1937; 309908 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Floyd, William, 1943; 309909 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley: News Clippings and Campaign Materials, 1952-1957; 309910 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Fordism by Carl Raushenbush (League for Industrial Democracy), 1937; 309911 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Foundaton of Catholics for Human Brotherhood (Union Donations), 1945-1946; 309912 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Hawaii: Statehood, undated; 309913 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - High School Teachers Association, [1929], 1933-1955; 309914 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - High School Teachers Association: Boycott of Unpaid Extracurricular Activities, 1951; 309915 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Hobbs Concentration Camp Bill, 1941, undated; 309919 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Horace Wiliams Philosophical Society, 1945; 309921 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Howard University Contract with UPN-CIO for Teaching Staff, 1947; 310065 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Intolerance at Gompers Vocational High School (Timothy F. Murray), 1940; 310066 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Is Hitler Dead? and Best Anti-Nazi Humor, 1939; 310067 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jefferson School of Social Science, 1946-1953, undated; 310068 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Joint Committee of Teachers' Organizations, 1933-1939, 1941; 310069 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1942-1957, undated; 310070 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Knickerbocker (William E.) Case, 1949-1951; 310071 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Labor Film Service, Inc., 1920, undated; 310072 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Labor Is on the March, A Play (Incomplete, with Handwritten Notes), undated; 310073 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Labor Issues: Various, 1932-1959, undated; 310074 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Lincoln School of Teachers College, Columbia University, 1926, 1929, 1936; 310087 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Literacy Test (New York State), undated; 310088 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Little Red School House, 1945; 310089 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Marzani, Carl, [1950]; 310090 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Methodist Federation for Social Service, 1942; 310091 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Milk Prices and the Penny Milk Program, 1941, undated; 310092 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., 1945-1947, undated; 310093 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - National Defense (Pre WW-II, Teachers' Point of View), 1940, undated; 310094 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - National Education Association, 1944-1945, undated; 310095 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - National Education Association: Various Printed Materials, 1934-1945; 310096 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - National Education Association: Various Printed Materials, 1946-1947; 310097 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - National Education Association: Various Printed Materials, 1947-1960, undated; 310098 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - New China through Her Children's Eyes, 1953; 310099 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - New York State Federation of Teachers Unions, 1937-1942, undated; 310100 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - New York State's Equal Pay Law, 1944; 310101 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Educational Issues, 1930-1958; 310102 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Educational Issues, 1959-1961, undated; 310103 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Political Issues, 1933-1961, undated; 310104 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Union Issues, 1940-1959; 310105 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Various, 1929, 1949-1959; 310106 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Ober Law, [1948]; 310107 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - On Scabs by Jack London, undated; 310108 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Outline of the New Deal Legislation of 1933-1934, 310109 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - The Paris Commune by Karl Marx: American Edition published by New York Labor News Company, 1920; 310110 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - People's Congress and Peace Exposition, Chicago, 1951; 310111 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pepper, Claude: An American Policy for Peace..., 1946; 310112 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Play Schools Association, 1945-1947; 310113 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Post-WWII Planning Conferences, 1943-1945; 310114 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Progressive Education, 1936, 1950-1955, undated; 310115 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Progressive Party, 1948, undated; 310116 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Public Education Association: Various Printed Materials, 1939-1957, undated; 310117 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Publications: After the War, Jun 1943; 310118 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Association of Teachers of Social Studies of New York City - ATSS Bulletin, 1944-1945; 310119 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Publications: BSC News (Better Schools Committee of the Southeast Bronx), May 1950-Jun 1950; 310120 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Bread and Butter, Feb 27, 1943; 310121 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Publications: Bulletin of the Teachers Alliance, 1940-1943; 310122 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Publications: College Newsletter, 1938-1947; 310123 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Publications: Columbia University, Jan 1951, Feb 1960; 310124 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Publications: The Disinherited Speak, Letters from Sharecroppers, undated; 310125 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Publications: Dynamo (High School of Science Creative Writing Club), Jun 1943; 310129 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Publications: Economic Notes, 1956-1960; 310130 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Publications: Father Knickerbocker's Stepchild, Summary of an Impartial Inquiry into the Status of Public Libraries and Librarians of Greater New York, [1938]; 310131 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Publications: Foreign Policy Reports - Bretton Woods Monetary Conference Plans and Achievements, 1944; 310132 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Publications: Fusion Society (Parody), undated; 310133 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Publications: Greater New York Bulletin of the Merchants' Association of New York, 1933; 310144 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Publications: High School Teachers Association Bulletin, 1928, 1932; 310145 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Publications: How One Race Judges Another for Physical Attractiveness, 1932; 310146 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Publications: In Fact, 1940-1950; 310147 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Publications: Joint Committee of Teachers Organizations - Bulletin, 1934-1947; 310148 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Publications: Letters to Dad (CIO), undated; 310149 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Publications: Mexican Labor News (CIO), 1943-1944; 310150 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Publications: National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools - Citizens and their Schools, 1951-1953; 310151 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Publications: National Citizens Council for Better Schools - Better Schools, 1957, 1958; 310152 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Publications: Negro High-School Graduates and Nongraduates, Relation of their Occupational Status to Certain School Experiences, 1940; 310153 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Publications: New University Thought (Autumn), 1962; 310154 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Publications: NY State Federaton of Labor - Proceedings, 71st Annual Convention and Bulletin, 1934, 1938; 310155 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Publications: New York Teachers Guild - The Bulletin and Guild Teachers, 1938, 1941, 1943; 310156 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Publications: News of Africa, 1942; 310170 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Publications: Newsletter of the Commission on Teacher Education of the American Council on Education, 1941-1942; 310171 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Publications: Progressive Education Association, 1933-1944; 310172 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Publications: Propaganda Analysis (The Institute for Propaganda Analysis, Inc.), Sep 1, 1940; 310173 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Publications: Report on World Affairs, Johannes Steel, Sep 1947, Feb 1950; 310174 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Publications: Russian Language, 1952; 310175 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Publications: School Life, Sep 1953; 310176 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Publications: Social Justice, Sep 15, 1941; 310177 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Publications: Soviet Aggression: Myth or Reality, Corliss Lamont, 1951; 310178 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Publications: Teacher Salaries, 1947, 1948, 1951; 310179 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Publications: Toward Freedom, Nov 1954; 310180 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Publications: Trends and Tides, Jan 1948 - Mar 1948; 310181 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Publications: Union Teacher (The Federation of Teachers Unions, State of New York), 1938; 310182 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Publications: Why the British People Fight, 1940; 310183 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Quinn, May A., 1943, 1950, undated; 310184 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Reading Retardation, Jan 1954 - May 1954; 310195 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Reading Retardation, Jun 1954 -1959, undated; 310196 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Reform Our Study, Mao Tse Tung, 1955; 310197 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Rhodes School Controversy, 1946; 310198 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Rockwell, George Lincoln: Controversy over Speech Permit (NYC), 1960; 310199 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, 1952-1954; 310200 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Roster of Teachers in the Public Schools of Camden, NJ, 1948; 310201 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Schappes, Morris: Statements, Information Letters, Press, Flyers, 1941-1943, undated; 310202 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - School Financing: School Bond Issue Referendum (Nov 3, 1959), 310203 (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - School Financing: Various Publications and Documents, 1933-1938; 310204 (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - School Financing: Various Publications and Documents, 1940-1948; 310214 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - School Financing: Various Publications and Documents, 1951-1958; 310215 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - School for Democracy, 1942, undated; 310216 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - School Relief Fund, 1932; 310217 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Segregation/Discrimination in Schools, 1945-1961, undated; 310218 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Segregation/Discrimination in Schools: Harlem, 1948, 1959, undated; 310219 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Separation of Church and State: "The Catholic Hierarchy's Challenge to American Institutions" - Manuscripts, Drafts, Notes, 1947; 310220 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Separation of Church and State: "The Catholic Hierarchy's Challenge to American Institutions" - Manuscripts, Drafts, Notes, undated; 310221 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Separation of Church and State: "The Catholic Hierarchy's Challenge to American Institutions" - Manuscript, 1952; 310222 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Separation of Church and State: "Dictation of School Policies by the Catholic Hierarchy" - Manuscript, 1949; 310223 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Separation of Church and State: School Prayer, Released Time and Other Education Issues, 1947-1952, undated; 310224 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Shubert, Sara C., Agnes Doe and Cecelia C. Pollack v. Board of Education of the City of New York (Permanent Substitutes), 1943; 310225 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Sobell, Martin: Articles, Statements, Flyers, Solicitations, Correspondence, 1956-1960, undated; 310226 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Social Studies, 1940-1941, 1948, 1951-1958, undated; 310246 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Social Studies: Attacks on Textbooks, 1940-1941; 310247 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Socialism: Father Gassoniana by Daniel DeLeun, 1914; 310248 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Socialist Party, 1935-1937, undated; 310249 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Socialist Party: New Jersey, 1917, undated; 310250 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Solicitations and Advertisements, 1942-1961, undated; 310251 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Song Lyrics: Various, 1938, undated; 310252 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Spanish Civil War: Correspondence, Articles, Solicitation, 1936-1937, undated; 310253 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Spanish Civil War: Refugee Relief - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 1938-1948, undated; 310254 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Spanish Civil War: Refugee Relief - Various Organizations, 1939-1945, undated; 310255 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Spanish Civil War: Refugee Relief - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1944-1952, undated; 310256 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Statements, Newsletters, Brochures, Minutes: Various Organizations, 1937-1950, undated; 310257 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Teacher Retirement/Pension System, 1929-1950, undated; 310258 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1937, 1953; 310259 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Unemployed Teachers, 1930-1941, undated; 310260 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - United Nations, 1942-1947; 310261 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Various Teacher Organizations: Federation of Women High School Teachers, 1936; 310262 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Various Teacher Organizations: Houston Teachers Association and Syracuse Teachers Association, 1939, 1943; 310263 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Various Teacher Organizations: San Mateo County Teachers Association, 1940; 310264 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals, 1937-1940, undated; 310265 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Boston (AFT), 1942; 310266 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Buffalo (AFT), 1938-1941; 310267 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Chicago (AFT), 1937-1941; 310268 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Chicago (AFT) - Chicago Union Teacher, 1937-1938; 310269 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Ohio - Akron, Cincinnati, Cleveland (AFT), 1937-1940, undated; 310270 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Philadelphia (AFT) - The Philadelphia Teacher, 1937-1939; 310271 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals: Seattle (AFT), 1938; 310272 (Box 17, Folder 41)